Guide to the Charles Henri Ford Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- 1946-1982 Acquisitions, 1928-1947; 5; (7 boxes)
  - Writings, 1937; Series II; 0.25; (1 box)
    Series II, Writings, is housed in Box 3 and contains only two of Charles Henri Ford's literary efforts. His poetic style of combining radio jazz, iambic pentameter, surrealist imagery, and sonnet forms is displayed in his collection of verse, The Garden of Disorder. Advertisements, including a list of reviewers, drafts, page proofs, and dust covers from the Europa Press can be found in the collection. There is also a draft of Ford's autobiographical novel, "I Will Be What I Am," about his life from 1922-34. The first section of the unpublished novel concerns his years in boarding school and college along with the year he edited Blues. According to his diary entries for this period, he was a voracious reader and an avid movie buff. In the second part of the novel, he moves to Paris and communicates the events of his life through a series of letters, mainly to his mother and his friend, Parker Tyler. The letters to Tyler are very personal and even describe a treatment Ford received in Paris for a painful case of gonorrhea. Ford's letters also concern his efforts to get The Young and Evil published. It was rejected by many publishers because of its "scandalous" focus on homosexuality. One New York publisher wrote, "I read with infinite pleasure your brilliant novel, but I could not think of publishing it as a book--life is too short and the jails unsanitary" (Box 3, folder 209). It was finally published, however, by the Obelisk Press in Paris. Part three of the novel includes Ford's travels in Europe and North Africa, particularly in Morocco, with "Carmita." He had very little money at this time and apparently was supported by his father and friends. The novel ends in part IV with Ford planning to return to New York in 1934.
    - BOOKS
      - The Garden of Disorder
        - Early typescript of title page, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 201)
        - Typescript, corrected, 1937 Oct 7 (Box 3, Folder 202)
        - Page proof, corrected, 1937 Nov-Dec (Box 3, Folder 203)
        - Page proof, corrected, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 204)
        - Dust jackets, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 205)
        - Paper samples, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 206)
        - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 207)
      - "I Will Be What I Am"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 208-11)
    - POETRY
      - "The Desire to Be in Two Places at Once": typescript, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 212)
      - "Dime Movie": typescript, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 213)
      - "Morning, Noon and Night": typescript (Box 3, Folder 214)
  - Journal Editing, 1941-47; Series III; 0.75; (2 boxes)
    Organized into two subseries: Blues and View.
    Series III, Journal Editing, is housed in Boxes 4-5 and contains material about the little magazines Blues and View. The Blues pieces include typescripts of advertisements composed by Parker Tyler and manuscripts submitted for publication, including a poem by Forrest Anderson. According to the New York Herald Tribune on December 23, 1928, Blues planned to publish poetry and short stories of an experimental nature in an attempt to stage a "more complete revolt against the cliche, the banal, the commonplace." Many of the reviews of Blues, which Ford saved in an oversize scrapbook housed in Box 6, folder 327, are favorable. Gremin Zorn of the Long Island Press, for example, wrote in February 1929 that "the first issue blossoms defiantly in the wasteland of our magazines; the contents are robust, contemporary."
    The View material consists of drawings and manuscripts submitted for publication, including a typescript of William Carlos Williams's review of André Breton's Young Cherry Trees Secured Against Hares (Box 5, folder 326) and Edith Sitwell's notes on poetry, geometry, light, color, time, and space (Box 5, folder 323). There is a cover design by Eugene Berman and a pen and ink illustration by Neal Thomas. There are also a large number of photographs of art work by painters, such as John Tunnard and Florine Stettheimer, and sculptors such as David Hare. A few photographs of artists, including René Magritte, Man Ray, and Morris Hirshfield, are filed in Box 5, folder 297. View sponsored a concert series of "The New Jazz" in 1944, which featured Pearl Bailey, Barney Bigard, Don Byas, Erroll Garner, and Stuff Smith. Photographs of these musicians, including Coleman Hawkins, are found in Box 5, folder 298. The oversized View scrapbook, housed in Box 6, folder 332, also contains programs, articles, and reviews of the series. In addition, there are advertisements and reviews of View editions, art exhibits sponsored by View at the Hugo Gallery, lectures by Jean Paul Sartre arranged by View at Carnegie Hall, and futurist drama at the View -supported Theater Ubu. There are also articles about the ban of the December, 1943 issue of View by the U. S. Post Office because it featured nudes by Leon Kelley and reproduced Picasso's "Le Minotaure." A few odd photographs of objects such as primitive masks from The Museum of Modern Art's 1946 exhibition on "Arts of the South Seas" complete the collection. Joseph Cornell's 1944 original photo-collage "A Watch-case for Marcel Duchamp", which had been previously misidentified as a photograph, was mounted in its own box in 1998.
    - BLUES
      - Advertisements
        - Typescripts and printed material (Box 4, Folder 215)
          See also: Box 6, folder 327
      - Manuscripts
        - Abel, Lionel, "Seventeen-Year-Old Poets": typescript of translation, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 216)
        - Anderson, Forrest, "error versus error": typescript (Box 4, Folder 217)
        - Crosby, Harry, "The House of Ra" and "The Trumpet of Departure": typescripts (Box 4, Folder 218)
        - Giovanelli, Felix, "Extra Added Attraction": printed version, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 219)
        - Jackson, Laura Riding, essays: typescripts and corrected page proofs (Box 4, Folder 220)
        - Zukovsky, Louis, "Five Poems" (1926-1927): holograph, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - VIEW
      - Advertisements
        - Typescripts and printed material, 1942-47, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 222)
        - See also: Box 6, folder 332
      - Graphics
        - Drawings by Eugene Berman, [1947] (Box 4, Folder 223)
        - Drawings by Neal Thomas, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 224)
        - Drawings by unidentified artists, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 225)
        - Engraving by Mary Wykeham, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 226)
        - Newspaper illustrations, 1945, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 227)
        - Photographs by Francis Lee, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 228)
        - Photographs by Raoul Hausman, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 229)
        - Photographs of art
          - Adam Henri G., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 230)
          - Albright, Ivan Le Lorraine, 1945-46 (Box 4, Folder 231)
          - Bosch, Hieronymus, n.d (Box 4, Folder 232)
          - Cézanne, Paul, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 233)
          - Chagall, Marc, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 234)
          - Coutaud, Lucien, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 235)
          - Degas, Edgar, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 236)
          - Delvaux, Paul, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 237)
          - Dominguez, Oscar, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 238)
          - Donati, Enrico, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 239)
          - Dubuffet, Jean, 1944, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 240)
          - Eilshemius, Louis M., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 241)
          - Fett, William F., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 242)
          - Francés, Esteban, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 243)
          - Gogh, Vincent Van, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 244)
          - Greco, El, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 245)
          - Guerin, Jean, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 246)
          - Hare, David, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 247)
          - Harnett, William, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 248)
          - Herold, Jacques, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 249)
          - Hirshfield, M., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 250)
          - Klee, Paul, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 251)
          - Lam, Wifredo, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 252)
          - Laurens, Henri, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 253)
          - Léger, Fernand (Box 4, Folder 254)
          - Leonid [Berman], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 255)
          - Lobo, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 256)
          - Louis, Seraphine, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 257)
          - MacIver, Loren, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 258)
          - Magritte, René, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 259)
          - Martinez-Pedro, Louis, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 260)
          - Massey, Joe, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 261)
          - Matisse, Henri, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 262)
          - Miró, Joan, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 263)
          - Monastery Chilander: fresco of the Trinity (Box 4, Folder 264)
          - Mondrian, Piet (Box 4, Folder 265)
          - Moore, Henry, 1946-47, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 266)
          - Nevelson, Louise, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 267)
          - Noguchi, Isamu, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 268)
          - O'Keeffe, Georgia, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 269)
          - Orloff, Lillian, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 270)
          - Ozenfant, Amédée, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 271)
          - Paalen, Wolfgang, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 272)
          - Picasso, Pablo, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 273)
          - Pickett, Joseph, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 274)
          - Pollock, Jackson, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 275)
          - Rain, Charles, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 276)
          - Ray, Man, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 277)
          - Rothko, Mark, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 278)
          - Rouault, Georges, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 279)
          - Roysmerwal, Marinus van, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 280)
          - Ryder, Albert P., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 281)
          - Sage, Kay, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 282)
          - Seligmann, Kurt, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 283)
          - Stettheimer, Florine, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 284)
          - Tamayo, Rufino, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 285)
          - Tanguy, Yves, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 286)
          - Tanning, Dorothea, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 287)
          - Tchelitchew, Pavel, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 288)
          - Tobey, Mark, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 289)
          - Tschacbasov, Nahum, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 290)
          - Tunnard, John, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 291)
          - Ubac, Raoul, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 292)
          - Vedovelli, A. M., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 293)
          - Waste, Henrie, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 294)
          - Wols, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 295)
          - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 296)
        - Photographs of artists and others, 1945, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 297)
        - Photographs of black musicians, 1943-44, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 298)
        - Photographs of engravings, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 299)
        - Photographs of Gotham Book Mart, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 300)
        - Photographs of objects
          - Ant dwelling, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 301)
          - Primitive masks, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 302)
          - Terra cotta brick, Han Dynasty (Box 5, Folder 303)
          - [Empty folder] (Box 5, Folder 304)
        - Reproductions, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 305)
      - Manuscripts
        - Arm, Hilary, "Riches of Word of Image": typescript and galley (Box 5, Folder 306)
        - B., C., reviews: typescripts, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 307)
        - Bentley, Eric, "The Old Vic, the Old Critics, and the New Generation": typescript (Box 5, Folder 308)
        - Bewley, Marius, "The Virile Elizabethans": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 309)
        - Bowles, Paul, "By the Water": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 310)
        - Downer, Alan S., "The Drama Lover as Critic": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 311)
        - Goodman, Paul, "The Big Little Magazines": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 312)
        - Kochnitzky, Léon, "A Vos Ordres": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 313)
        - McM., E. "Brief Notices": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 314)
        - MacManus, Everett, "Condition Critical": typescript (Box 5, Folder 315)
        - Magritte, René, "La Ligne de Vie": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 316)
        - Mariën, Marcel, "Le Noeud Gordien": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 317)
        - Nougé, Paul, "L'Experience Souveraine": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 318)
        - Nougé, Paul, "Grand Air": typescript, 1944 Jan (Box 5, Folder 319)
        - Roditi, Edouard, "Good Spade Work in Renaissance Art": printed version, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 320)
        - Schapiro, Meyer, "On a Painting of Van Gogh": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 321)
        - Seligmann, Kurt, "Magic and the Arts": typescript, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 322)
        - Sitwell, Edith, "Notes from a Poet's Notebook": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 323)
        - Tyler, Parker, "Fourteen Minus One": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 324)
        - Williams, William Carlos, "Dr. Williams to Mr. Ford": typescript, 1941 Oct 23 (Box 5, Folder 325)
        - Williams, William Carlos, "The Genius of France": typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 326)
  - Oversize, 1928-1947; 1.5; (1 box)
    - BLUES
      - Reviews
        - Scrapbook, 1928-31 (Box 35)
    - VIEW
      - Graphics
        - Cover designs, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 328)
        - "A Watch-case for Marcel Duchamp," photo-collage by Joseph Cornell, 1944 Dec (Box 7, Folder 328a)
        - Photographs by Andre de Dienes (Box 6, Folder 329)
        - Photographs of art
          - Brancusi, Constantin, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 330)
          - Smith, Angus, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 331)
      - Reviews
        - Scrapbook, 1944-47 (Box 36)
- August 2004 Acquisition, 1918-2003; 21.95; (27 boxes)
  Organized into eight series: I. Correspondence, 1918-2002. II. Notebooks, 1950-1999. III. Writings, 1977-1997. IV. Writings of Others, 1970-2002. V. Art Files, 1956-2001. VI. Printed Material, 1942-1977. VII. Personal and Financial Papers, 1948-2003. VIII. Unsorted Papers, 1955-2003.
  Purchased from George Robert Minkoff, Inc., on the Alfred Z. Baker, Jr. Fund, 2004.
  - Correspondence, 1918-2002; Series I; 4; (4 boxes)
    Arranged alphabetically, with unsorted correspondence and postcards filed at the end.
    - Barnes, Djuna, 1932-1933 (Box 8)
    - Baum, Timothy, 1976 January 15 (Box 8)
    - Beaton, Cecil, 1935-1958 (Box 8)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1940 October 7 (Box 8)
    - Bowles, Paul, 1931-1938 (Box 8)
    - Bourdon, David, 1975 December 20 (Box 8)
    - Boyle, Kay, 1975 December 16 (Box 8)
    - Brainard, Joe, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Brooks, Romaine, undated (Box 8)
    - Cage, Betty, secretary at View, 1946 (Box 8)
    - Cadmus, Paul, 1951 October (Box 8)
    - Calder, Alexander "Sandy", 1976 (Box 8)
    - Campbell, Sandy and Donald Windham, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Carrington, Leonora, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Codrescu, André, 1971 October 8 (Box 8)
    - Cornell, Joseph, 1939-1954 (Box 8)
    - Cremonini, Leonardo, 1953-1956 (Box 8)
    - Crosby, Caresse, 1964 June 18 (Box 8)
    - Crowley, Mart, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    - DeLamar, Alice, 1944 (Box 8)
    - de Noailles, Marie-Laure, 1937-1938 (Box 8)
    - Dewitt, _____, 1944 December 14 (Box 8)
    - DiPrima, Diane, 1971, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Eggleston, Rosa and Bill, [1979] (Box 8)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Fini, Leonor, 1931-1956 (Box 8)
    - Flanner, Janet, 1940-1964 (Box 8)
    - Giorno, John, [1975] (Box 8)
    - Gruem, John and Caroline R., 1975 December 15 (Box 8)
    - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1944-1950 (Box 8)
    - Gysin, Biron, 1964-1975 (Box 8)
    - Heliczer, Piero, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Higgins, Dick, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    - Hoyningen-Huene, George, 1956 (Box 8)
    - Hussey, Howard, 1975 (Box 8)
    - James, Edward, undated (Box 8)
    - Janis, Sidney, 1946 (Box 8)
    - Joans, Ted, 1985-2002 (Box 8)
    - Johnson, Ray, undated (Box 8)
    - Kennedy, Blanchard, 1940-1951 (Box 8)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1937 (Box 8)
    - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Lam, Wilfredo, undated (Box 8)
    - Lamantia, Philip, 1944 (Box 8)
    - Laughlin, James, 1951 (Box 8)
    - Lennon, John, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Lil Picard, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    - Lindamood, Peter, 1939 (Box 8)
    - Magallanes, Nick, 1941-1976 (Box 8)
    - Malanga, Gerard, 1976-1978 (Box 8)
    - Merrill, James, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Miles, Sylvia, undated (Box 8)
    - Morris, _____, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Norse, Harold, 1975, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Ono, Yoko, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Pound, Ezra, 1927 (Box 8)
    - Rader, Dotson, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Roditi, Edouard, 1975-1988 (Box 8)
    - Rorem, Ned, 1975-1994 (Box 8)
    - Rosco, Jerry, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Sage, Kay, undated (Box 8)
    - Scavullo, Francesco, 1971 (Box 8)
    - Schneemann, Carolee, undated (Box 8)
    - Scott, Zachary, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Stein, Gertrude, undated (Box 8)
    - Stettheimer, Florine, 1942, 1944 (Box 8)
    - Tanguey, Yves and Kay Sage, 1948 (Box 8)
    - Tanning, Dorothea, 1947-1998 (Box 8)
    - Tavel, Ronald, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1975, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Tyler, Parker, 1928-1948; 2 (Box 8)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1935-1948 (Box 8)
    - Vidal, Gore, 1976-1981 (Box 8)
    - Watson, Peter, 1939-1949 (Box 8)
    - Williams, Jonathan, 1979 December 21 (Box 8)
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Windham, Donald, 1997 May 10 (Box 8)
    - Carmita, undated (Box 8)
    - Cato, 1945 (Box 8)
    - Millicent, undated (Box 8)
    - Postcards, 1930-1975 (Box 8)
    - Tyler, Parker, 1929-1972; 16 (Box 9)
    - Ford, C. H., postcards to his mother, 1934 (Box 9)
    - Ford, C. H., postcards, 1932-1956 (Box 9)
    - Ford, Ruth, postcards, 1930-1976 (Box 9)
    - Cohen, Ira, postcards, 1977-1990 (Box 9)
    - Solt, John, postcards, 1994-1999 (Box 9)
    - Tillman, Lynne, postcards, 1975-1988 (Box 9)
    - Postcards, 1953 (Box 9)
    - Helion postcard, undated (Box 9)
    - DeLamar postcards, 1939-1948 (Box 9)
    - Bark, R., postcards, 1989-2001 (Box 9)
    - Postcards, 1967-2001 (Box 9)
    - Dietrick postcards, 1946-1948 (Box 9)
    - Postcards, 1932-1998 (Box 10)
    - Bokris, Victor, postcards, undated (Box 10)
    - Postcards, 1948-1983 (Box 10)
    - Bermon, Eugene, postcard, 1954 (Box 10)
    - Gorer postcards, 1940-1950 (Box 10)
    - Dania postcards, 1954-1976 (Box 10)
    - Clerichi postcards, 1953-1955 (Box 10)
    - Postcards (empty envelope), undated (Box 10)
    - Bently, Eve, postcards, 1951 (Box 10)
    - Baum, Tim, postcards, 1982 (Box 10)
    - Field, Andrew, postcards, 1980-1982 (Box 10)
    - Codrescu postcards, 1975-1981 (Box 10)
    - Edel, Leon postcards, 1981 (Box 10)
    - Embiricos postcards, 1945-1951 (Box 10)
    - Dickenson postcards, 1985 (Box 10)
    - De La Grosse, H. L., postcards, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Boultenhouse, Charles, postcards, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
    - Vogel, Amos, postcards, undated (Box 10)
    - Postcards, 1976-2002; 4 (Box 10)
    - Delarue, Allison, postcard, undated (Box 10)
    - Empty envelopes, 1975 (Box 10)
    - Dreva, Jerry, postcards, 1977-1980 (Box 10)
    - Postcards, 1970-2000; 2 (Box 10)
    - Calas postcards, undated (Box 10)
    - Postcards, 1931-2001; 2 (Box 10)
    - Postcards, not to C. H. Ford, 1918 (Box 10)
    - Postcards, 1935-2002; 4 (Box 10)
    - Miles, Martin, postcards, 1983-1999 (Box 10)
    - Postcards, 1954-2001; 8 (Box 10)
    - Burke, Ronnie, 1988-2002; 5 (Box 10)
    - Unsorted, 1933-1940 (Box 10)
    - Mail Orders, 1993-1994 (Box 10)
    - Memo and supplement re: "Water from a bucket", 1965 (Box 10)
    - Roditi, Edouard, 1951-1954 (Box 10)
    - [Joans?], Ted, undated (Box 11)
    - Lehrman, Karen, 1994-1997 (Box 11)
    - Mayo, 1964 (Box 11)
    - Broe, Mary Lynn, 1990-1999 (Box 11)
    - Furnace, Franklin, 1980 (Box 11)
    - Business correspondence, 1972-1999 (Box 11)
    - Ford literary letters, material requests, UBU Gallery material, 1988-2000 (Box 11)
    - Vail, Karole, 1997-1998 (Box 11)
    - Business correspondence, 1968-1999 (Box 11)
    - Postcards, announcements, 1996-1999 (Box 11)
    - Unsorted, 1991-2001; 2 (Box 11)
    - Cards, correspondence, 1969-1998; 2 (Box 11)
    - Cards, invitations, 1984-2000; 4 (Box 11)
    - Letters from friends, 1956-1998; 4 (Box 11)
    - "Notes/letters 2000", 1988-2000; 2 (Box 11)
    - Unsorted, 1965-2002; 5 (Box 11)
    - Names, addresses, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Notebooks, 1950-1999; Series II; 2; (2 boxes)
    - "Lizard Behind the Curtain," vol. 2, 1976 (Box 12)
    - "Bathtub Haikus", 1993-1994 (Box 12)
    - "Haiku", 1994 (Box 12)
    - "Haiku Autobiography", 1994 (Box 12)
    - "Haiku Group Title", undated (Box 12)
    - "24 Haikus for Gertrude Stein", undated (Box 12)
    - "Festive Occassions", undated (Box 12)
    - Notebook, "III", undated (Box 12)
    - Notebook, "IV", undated (Box 12)
    - Notebooks, 1995-1999, undated; 7 (Box 12)
    - Address book, undated (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1967 April-December (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1968 December 22-1969 May 27 (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Daily Planner, 1993 (Box 13)
    - Daily Planner, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "Book II", 1950 April 2 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "Book III", 1950 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "Book IV", 1950 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "Book V", 1950 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "Dionysus/Images Italienne", 1950-1952 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, 1953-1954 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "Painting Notes and Poems and Theatre Notes and Manuscript for The Irresponsibles ", 1958 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "I", 1962 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "V", 1962 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "Someone to Eat with: A Memoir by Higdon Cato", 1963 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "Cretan Souvenirs + SP Members", 1967 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
      "Gleaned, April 16 1973"
    - Notebook, "Multiple Exposures", 1973 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, 1973 April 16 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "Paris", 1974 October 11-18 (Box 13)
    - Notebook, "Vol. I, Operation Minotaur", 1976 (Box 13)
  - Writings, 1977-1997; Series III; 1; (1 box)
    - "To Nexus, Dayton, Ohio", 1994-1997 (Box 14)
    - Om Krishna, 1979-1991 (Box 14)
    - "Om Krishna first typed draft", 1977 (Box 14)
    - "Minotaur Sutra", 1998 (Box 14)
    - "Confessions of a Freak," manuscript, undated (Box 14)
    - "Poet in Kathmandu: An Oriental Idyll," manuscript, undated; 3 (Box 14)
    - "Surrealism in View", 1970 (Box 14)
    - "The Silver Dracula", undated (Box 14)
    - "Water from a Bucket," manuscript, undated; 3 (Box 14)
    - "Public Haiku", undated (Box 14)
    - "Charles Henri Ford, Catalyst Among the Poets," interview by Asako Kitaori and Gerard Malanga, 1997 (Box 14)
    - "Extra Pages from Public Haiku", [1996] (Box 14)
    - "Public Haiku", undated; 2 (Box 14)
    - Poetry, (including "Minotaur Sutra"), undated (Box 14)
    - Poetry rejects, undated (Box 14)
    - "Par Hasard," xerox, undated (Box 14)
  - Writings of Others and Associated Material, 1970-2002; Series IV; 1; (1 box)
    - "Charles Henri Ford: Catalyst Among Poets," interview by Asako Kitaori, undated (Box 15)
    - Writings of others, 1972-1992; 6 (Box 15)
    - Burk, Ronnie, "Sky* Boat", 2002 (Box 15)
    - Charles de [Vincennes], autobiography, manuscript, undated (Box 15)
    - Neiman, Catrina, "Acrobat in the Dark," manuscript (biography of Parker Tyler), 1988 December (Box 15)
    - Malanga, Gerald, "Gloss", 1973 (Box 15)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, "Pavel Fyodorovitch Tchelitchev", 1991 (Box 15)
    - "The Silver Dracula," an interview with Charles Henri Ford, undated (Box 15)
    - Die Aussenseite des Elementes 10, 1983 July (Box 15)
    - Die Aussenseite des Elementes 8, undated (Box 15)
    - Signed photograph of Geraldine Smith, 1996 May 13 (Box 15)
  - Art Files, 1956-2002; Series V; 1.58; (4 boxes)
    - Ford's prints, (copies), 1956-2001 (Box 16)
    - Photocopies, CHF (Box 16)
    - "Remote cutoff," (photocopies), 1999 (Box 16)
    - Photographs and photocopies, circa 2000 (Box 16)
    - Collages, 1991 (Box 16)
    - Collage, (photocopies), circa 1983 (Box 16)
    - Invitation and collage photocopies, 1982-1984 (Box 16)
    - Drawings, sketches and color photocopies, undated (Box 16)
    - Art photocopies, undated (Box 16)
    - Color photographs, undated (Box 16)
    - Color photocopies and papers, circa 2000 (Box 16)